He didn't know how to stop it... she did.
The Burning Bed is a crime, drama, tv movie film directed by Robert Greenwald.
An abused battered wife has had enough of husband beating up on her.
Everywhere she turns for help, there's not much anyone will do.
After he rapes her one night, she sets the bed on fire with him in it asleep.
Francine Hughes, played by Farrah Fawcett-Majors.
Mickey Hughes, played by Paul Le Mat.
Aryon Greydanus, played by Richard Masur.
Flossie Hughes, played by Grace Zabriskie.
Gaby, played by Penelope Milford.
Christy, Age 12, played by Christa Denton.
The Burning Bed is a 1984 American television crime drama film directed by Robert Greenwald and
starring Farrah Fawcett, Paul Le Mat, Richard Masur, Grace Zabriskie, and James Callahan.
Adapted by Rose Leiman Goldemberg from the 1980 non-fiction novel of the same name by Faith McNulty, it follows battered
housewife Francine Hughes and her trial for the murder of her abusive ex-husband, James Berlin "Mickey" Hughes.
Hughes set fire to the bed her husband was sleeping in at their Dansville, Michigan home on
March 9, 1977, after thirteen years of physical domestic abuse at his hands.
It aired on NBC on October 8, 1984.
The film premiered with a household share of 36.2, ranking it the seventeenth  highest rated
movie to air on network television and NBC's highest rated television movie.
The Burning Bed was met with critical acclaim, receiving eight
nominations at the 37th Primetime Emmy Awards.
It was also nominated for three Golden Globe Awards, with Le Mat winning the
award for Best Supporting Actor in a Miniseries or Television Film.
The film explores themes of domestic violence, killer, biting, angry, detached.
The tone is emotional.